Seasoned software architect and developer with 15 years in the field building and maintaining secure and scalable applications. Major experience with .NET/C#, SQL, JS and leading and managing development teams. Recent focus on cloud native applications, DevOps and Azure.

GitHub: https://github.com/aashishkoirala
Website/Blog: https://www.aashishkoirala.com

EXPERIENCE

Bond-Pro, Remote

Chief Architect, Software R&D, March 2019 - Present

Software architecture and development; leadership of Agile offshore team; DevOps

- Currently building the company's flagship cloud-based offering
- Working with .NET Core, Azure, EF Core, Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform among others

Vistra (formerly Radius), Bedford, MA

Architect, Software R&D, July 2012 - March 2019

Software architecture and development; leadership of Agile offshore team; DevOps

- Helped build and oversaw cloud based, microservices driven enterprise system. Ported
 entire system from on-premises to cloud-native Azure PaaS. Rewrote service and security
 stack, rebuilt frontend using Angular and SignalR.
- Led the team that built a sophisticated global payroll system from inception to release that supported over 150 customers across over 20 countries
- Helped build a homegrown workflow orchestration system based on Service Bus messaging

Verisk Health, Waltham, MA

Director of Engineering, August 2008 – July 2012

Software architecture and development; management of Agile onshore/offshore teams

- Took over a post-acquisition, undocumented and abandoned codebase, revived and reengineering it, thus becoming the resident expert for the system which served as the company's flagship healthcare analytics platform
- Introduced standard ETL tools and practices to the BI delivery process
- Helped transition the software development process from waterfall to Agile

D2Hawkeye Services, Kathmandu, Nepal

Software Architect, November 2004 – August 2008

Software architecture and development; management of multiple development teams

 Built, delivered and maintained 12 large scale projects using various technologies (including .NET, Java, C++, SQL Server and Oracle)

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Systems Engineering, Boston University, Boston, MA
B.E. in Computer Engineering, Tribhuvan University Institute of Engineering, Nepal

Tools/Tech/Practices

.NET/.NET Core C# ASP.NET Core

EF Core SignalR

JavaScript TypeScript Angular React Node

SQL Server, T-SQL

Azure Kubernetes Helm Docker Service Fabric

Microservices Twelve Factor SOA, DDD REST

MongoDB, CosmosDB ElasticSearch

Azure Service Bus RabbitMQ Kafka

OAuth2/OIDC, SAML OWASP Remediation

Git PowerShell Bash

DevOps
Azure DevOps
Jenkins
Terraform
Ansible
ELK
Prometheus
Application Insights

F# Go Rust